棒极了
Yes!
你激动什么
What are you so excited about?
最新一期的《天购》
It's the latest issue of "Skymall."
好极了
Oh--sweet.
不是吧  亲爱的
Oh, really, darling,
谁会订阅《天购》呢
Who subscribes to "Skymall"?
在飞机上看这些垃圾还不够吗
Isn't perusing all that dreck on the plane enough?
垃圾  妈妈  我要让你知道
Dreck? Mother, I will have you know,
这是通向
this is the gateway
世界上最炙手可热的新发明的大门
to the hottest new inventions in the world.
去哪能找到个遥控器
Where else can you find a remote control
上面装个开瓶器
that has a bottle... opener?
怎么了
What?
我想这是斯坦福大学寄给阿丽克西斯的决定函
I think it's Alexis' decision letter from Stanford University.
哦  孩子
Oh, kiddo.
你还好吗
You okay?
没事  只是它让一切都真实起来
Yeah, it just makes it so real.
她长得太快了
She grew up so fast.
你还指望什么呢
Well, what do you expect,
她永远都住在这里吗
her to live here forever?
她嘛  当然  你呢
Well, her? Yes. You...
说话当心
Mm. Watch it.
是决定函吗
Is that the mail?
是的
Oh, yeah.
你收到一封寄自"斯坦福"先生的
You have one here from a Mr. Stanford.
你认识他吗
Is that anyone you know?
怎么样
Well...
宝贝儿
Darling?
我没被录取
I-I didn't get in.
什么
What?
哦  宝贝儿  太遗憾了
Oh, sweetie. I'm so sorry.
但我都选课了
But I picked all my classes.
我买了T恤衫
I bought T-shirts.
我都计划好了
I-I had it all planned.
斯坦福大学怎么能认为她不够格呢
How could Stanford think she's not worthy?
她完美极了
She's perfect.
上周你还不愿意让她走呢
Last week you didn't want her to go.
是的  但是我不想让她不被录取
Yeah, but I didn't not want her to get in.
我确信她会被录取的
I was sure she would get in.
你都被录取了
You got in.
我现在可进不去
Well, I wouldn't now.
无论如何  先不管你受伤的自尊心
Anyway, put your bruised ego aside.
我认为她一定很伤心
I'm sure she's crushed.
实际上  她还在拒绝接受现实
Well, actually, right now she's in denial.
我走的时候   她在给招生人员打电话
When I left, she was on the phone with admissions,
跟他们说是他们犯了个错误
explaining to them, they'd made a mistake.
尸体在哪里
Where's the body?
问得太好了
That is an excellent question.
你是说没有尸体
You mean there's no body?
没有  只有大量血迹
Nope. Just lots of blood.
无论是谁
Whosever it is,
都活不成
there's no way they survived.
尸体究竟哪去了
So where'd they go?
你才是那个满腹不靠谱理论的人  卡塞尔
You're the one with all the crazy theories, Castle.
行尸走肉
Walking dead.
但种种迹象表明  尸体被移动过
But there are indications that the body was moved.
我想我知道是谁移动的
I think I know who moved it.
目击者说看到一辆无显著特征的白色货车
I got witnesses that said they saw an unmarked white van
在早上七点逃离现场
fleeing the scene just after 7:00 a.m.
他们看见驾驶员了吗
They get an eye on who was behind the wheel?
没有  但已经让巡警去找目击者
No, but we got unis canvassing for eyewitnesses
并查看五个街区内的
and checking every street-level security camera
街道监控录像
in a 5-block radius.
胎痕
Tire tracks.
好  提取胎痕
Okay, get a cast of the tire tread.
鉴证组或许能查到制造商和型号
C.S.U. might be able to get make and model.
这里有两组大小不同的鞋印
There's two different-size footprints.
至少有两个人
There was at least two of 'em.
但是鞋印上没有花纹
Yeah, but there's no tread on the footprints.
他们穿的一定是靴子
Must have been wearing booties.
失踪的尸体
Missing body,
掩盖踪迹的杀人犯
killers who literally cover their tracks,
有人感到突击刺客组织的气场了吗
anyone else getting a quick-strike assassin squad vibe?
得了吧  卡塞尔
Come on, Castle.
你不是说这是个秘密暗杀行动吧
You're not saying this is some kind of black-ops job?
不是我说的  是证据表明的
I'm not saying it. The evidence is saying it.
我猜这位老兄现在都葬身海底了
I'm betting this guy's buried at sea by now.
蕾妮  血迹中有个痕迹
Lanie, there's an imprint in the blood.
对  看起来像盒子或是箱子
Yeah, it looks like a box or a case.
可能是属于死者的
Might have been our victim's.
可能装着原子弹发射码
Nuclear launch codes probably.
莱恩  这里有个图案
Hey, Ryan, there's a pattern.
看看鉴证组能不能识别出来
Let's see if C.S.U. can I.D. it.
有问题吗
Is there a problem?
没有  对不住了
Oh, no. Sorry.
只是听到了这个词"图案"
It's just that word, "pattern".
我和珍妮还在筹备婚礼
Jenny and I, we're still registering for the wedding.
瓷器  银器  高脚器
China, silverware, stemware--
床单  更别提
sheets, not to mention...
鉴证组  痕迹  了解
C.S.U., imprint, got it.
我确定我查到了死因
I'm pretty sure I got a cause of death.
你是说除了大量失血
You mean besides massive blood loss?
枪击
Gunshots.
邻居在今早6点40听到两声枪响
Neighbors heard a pair go off at 6:40 this morning.
你确定是6点40吗
6:40? Are you sure?
百分之百确定  怎么了
Uh, positive. Why?
因为莱恩的目击者看见一辆货车
Because Ryan's witnesses saw a van
在七点的时候驶离这里
racing outta here at 7:00.
谁会杀了人还要等他们流血而亡
Who would kill someone, wait for them to bleed out,
再拿走他们的尸体
and then take their body?
我想这就排除了突击刺客组织的可能
I guess that rules out quick-strike assassin squad.
血迹中的痕迹就是你的最佳线索了
An imprint in the blood is your best lead?
根据针脚  鉴证组确定
Well, based on stitching, C.S.U. determined
手提箱是安德伍德牌的
that the briefcase is an Underwood,
价格高昂  本市只有两个商店有售
which is pricey, and only two local shops sell them.
他们把顾客的信息给我们了
They're giving us customer information.
听起来机会渺茫
Sounds like a long shot at best.
我们在等待胎痕分析
We're waiting on tire tread analysis,
莱恩警探正在核查
and Detective Ryan is overseeing the review
五十多个监控摄像头的录像寻找那辆货车
of over 50 security cameras looking for that van.
那死者呢  查到他身份了吗
What about the victim? Any closer to an I.D.?
从血液上看
Based on blood,
帕里什医生判定被害人为男性
Dr. Parish determined that our victim is a male.
所以我们正在查找那个区域男性
So we're looking for missing persons reports
失踪人口报告
of men in that area.
男性  你把死者范围缩小到男性了
Men? You've narrowed the victim pool down to men?
在纽约
Uh, well, in New York City,
这就排除了超过四百万名女性  所以
that actually eliminates over four million women, so...
卡塞尔先生  我真不知道
Mr. Castle, I don't know
市长究竟看上了你什么了
what the mayor sees in you,
但我知道你俩在某方面挺像的
but I know how you're alike.
那就是任期有限
He's term-limited.
或许要是我送她花
Maybe if I sent her flowers--
别  别想
No. No.
在没有尸体的情况下进行调查
So an investigation without a body...
这是前所未见吧
That's kinda new, right?
以往的谋杀案调查中
You know, there have been murder investigations
也有警方没找到尸体的先例
where authorities haven't found the body.
是啊  但是在那些案子中
Yeah, but in those cases,
他们总还知道死者是谁
they still know who the victim is.
四个孩子的父亲在垂钓途中失踪
Father of four disappears on fishing trip,
在家中的车库发现了血迹
blood found in family garage.
连死者是谁都不知道你又打算从何查起呢
Where do you start when you don't know who the victim is?
你
You...
你  你  你知道  你可以
You--you--you know, you could...
我们必须要找到尸体  对不
We really need to find the body, don't we?
对  差不多是这样
Yeah. Pretty much.
我或许能帮上忙
I may be able to help.
小巷附近的监控摄像头
Security cam footage near the alley
记录了三辆符合目击者描述的货车
clocked three vans that matched our witnesses' description,
两辆雪弗兰星旅和一辆福特伊克莱
two Astros and an Econoline.
是那辆福特伊克莱
It's the Econoline.
胎痕分析结果出来了
Tire tread analysis just came back.
找到车牌号了吗
You get plates?
是的  伊克莱注册在PW仓储名下
Yeah, the Econoline is registered to a P.W. Storage.
离犯罪现场只隔六个街区
It's only six blocks from our crime scene.
好吧  出发
All right. Let's go.
车牌号相匹配
Plates match.
门在那里
Door.
准备好了吗
Ready?
这是怎么回事
What the hell?
这里面是什么
What's in these things?
不知道
I don't know.
从它们的大小判断
Judging from the size of 'em,
真让人觉得是...
you'd almost expect there'd be...
人  天呐
people! Jeez.
是人
They're people.
他们被冻起来了
They look frozen.
这里到底是什么地方
What the hell is this place?
他们都是谁
Who are they all?
你们有没有一种想跑到大街上
Does anyone else have the sudden urge
大喊"他们在这里"的冲动
to run through the streets, screaming "They're here"?
我是贝克特探长
Yeah, this is detective Beckett.
-我要每个鉴证组的...  -有动静
- I need every C.S.U. tech...  - Movement.
十点钟方向有动静
Movement, 10:00.
纽约警局  举起你们的手
NYPD! Show us your hands!
不要开枪  不要开枪
Don't shoot! Don't shoot!
马上  马上
Now! Now!
转过身去
Turn around.
我们只是在做本职工作
We're just doing our job.
你们的工作是杀了人然后把他们冻起来
Killing and freezing people is your job?
不  我们到的时候他已经死了
No. He was already dead when we arrived to pick him up.
我们为帕威工作  一个人体冷冻公司
We work for Passageway, a cryonics company.
-人体冷冻  -转过来
- Cryonics. - Turn around.
这就能解释那一屋子的人体冰棒了
That explains the roomful of human popsicles.
他们都和我们签了合约
They all have contracts with us.
我们把他们冷冻起来
We cryopreserve them.
然后在能够治愈死亡的科幻未来
To be brought back to life in a science-fiction future
再让他们起死回生
where death has a cure.
他们能把我冻到婚礼那天吗
Think they can put me under till the wedding?
你们怎么会在我们之前就知道他已经死了
How did you know he was dead before we did?
他戴着一个配有脉搏监视器
He was wearing a bio-watch
和定位系统的生物手表
with a pulse monitor and GPS.
客户的脉搏停止时我们会马上接到通知
We're notified immediately when a client's pulse stops.
我们15分钟后到达了他的所在地
We were there in 15 minutes.
这可以解释时间上的问题
That explains the timeline problem.
就算这是真的  你们怎么想的
Even if that's true, what were you thinking,
居然移动一名枪击案的死者
moving a shooting victim?
你们为什么不报警
Why didn't you call 9-1-1?
我们不能浪费时间
We couldn't wait.
对于人体冷冻  一分一秒都是宝贵的
In cryonics, every minute counts.
我们必须尽快将他冷冻起来
We had to get him frozen as quickly as possible
以确保他的大脑能够存活
to keep his brain alive.
他的大脑没有存活
His brain isn't alive.
他的大脑已经死亡了  他已经死亡了
It's dead. He's dead.
这就是个见仁见智的问题了
That's a matter of opinion.
我是阿里·维斯博士
Dr. Ari Weiss,
帕威公司的首席执行官
C.E.O. of Passageway.
这是我的律师强尼·罗森
This is my attorney, Johnny Rosen.
我猜想你们应该有很多问题
I imagine you have many questions.
是的  首先你们从我的犯罪现场
Yeah, starting with who's the murder victim
带走的死者是谁
you took from my crime scene?
他名叫莱斯特·哈密顿
His name is Lester Hamilton--
哈德逊大学的生物学教授
a biology professor at Hudson University.
-你去核查一下  -这就查
- Can you call it in?  - I'm on it.
他碰巧也是我在
He also happens to be
哈佛医学院时的一位老朋友
an old friend from Harvard Medical School.
他的英年早逝真是讽刺
It's ironic he died so young.
为什么
Why is that?
他生前在延长寿命技术领域
He conducted cutting-edge research developing
做前沿研究
life-extension techniques.
看来研究的不怎么成功
Not that it did him any good.
这么说他和你一起工作
So he worked with you?
不是
No.
莱斯特专注于怎样在死前延长寿命
Lester focused on how to extend life before death.
我创建帕威是为了人们死后
I created Passageway in order to preserve the hope
在未来能有重生的希望
of future life, after death.
你这里有什么名人吗
You got any celebrities in here?
泰德·威廉斯[美国著名棒球运动员]
Ted Williams?
杰克·福斯特[神威漫画著名超级英雄]
Jack Frost?
我们不能讨论我们的客户
We don't discuss our clients.
但你必须得讨论这一个
Well, you're gonna have to discuss this one.
莱斯特·哈密顿是被谋杀的
Lester Hamilton was murdered,
我的法医到了之后
and my M.E. will be taking custody of his body
会带走他的尸体
as soon as she gets here.
探长  哈密顿教授是我们的客户
Detective, our client-- Professor Hamilton--
在他死后将他的遗体冷冻起来
has an iron-clad agreement with Passageway
是他和帕威之间不可动摇的协议
to have his body cryopreserved upon his death.
没有法院令  他哪也不能去
Short of a court order, he's not going anywhere.
而且任何带走他的企图都将
And any attempt to take him would constitute
被视为侵权行为
tortious interference,
我们会将你和纽约警局告得一穷二白
and we would sue you and the NYPD into oblivion.
好的  知道了
Okay. Got it.
检察官在这件案子上帮不了我们
D.A. won't back us up on this one.
他们说这方面的判例法很含糊
They say that the case law is murky.
肯定含糊
I'll say it's murky.
一名研究寿命延长技术的学者被害
A life-extension researcher is killed,
然后一个可疑的人体冷冻公司
then a shadowy cryonics company
偷走了他的尸体
absconds with the body?
一切的证据都说明这里有
This has all the hallmarks of a vast
一个巨大而不可告人的阴谋
and insidious conspiracy.
我还在考虑该怎样向盖茨解释
I'm still trying to figure out how to explain it to Gates.
他们偷了我们的被害人还威胁要告我们
They steal our victim and then threaten to sue us?
长官  这是一个法律上的鸡和蛋的问题
Sir, it's a legal chicken-and-egg problem.
因为哈密顿的尸体在私人领地内
Since Hamilton's body is on private property,
没有搜查令我们拿不到尸体
we can't get it without a warrant,
但是要拿到搜查令也不容易
but it's gonna be tough to get a warrant,
因为没有尸体
because without the body,
我们甚至无法证明他是被谋杀的
we can't even prove he was murdered.
这些故弄玄虚的话是他们的律师告诉你的
You get that doublespeak from their counsel?
不  长官  我母亲是一名律师
No, sir. My mother was a lawyer.
不管怎么样  相信我
Anyway, trust me
他们肯定会这么辩解的
this is the argument that they will make.
那好  我们现在知道些什么
Okay. Then where are we?
人体冷冻公司技术人员说
Well, the cryonics technician said that
哈密顿胸前中了两枪
Hamilton was shot twice in the chest.
他们把死者的衣服给了我们
They turned over his clothes,
根据衬衫上的洞
and based on the holes in the shirt,
看上去是大口径子弹所致
it looks like it was a large-caliber bullet.
他钱包里还有钱
There's still money in his wallet,
说明不是普通的抢劫
suggesting it wasn't a random mugging.
那个公文包呢
Well, what about the briefcase?
技术人员说现场没有公文包
Technician said that there wasn't a briefcase at the scene.
我给哈密顿的妻子打了电话
I called up Hamilton's wife.
她十分肯定今早他出门前
She was adamant that he left the apartment this morning
手上拿了个公文包
with a briefcase in hand.
她和菲利普·博伊德博士正在赶来
She's on her way in right now with a-- a Dr. Philip Boyd.
他是哈密顿先生的同事
He's a colleague of Mr. Hamilton's.
什么事
Yes.
哈密顿在哈德逊大学的办公室
Hamilton's office at Hudson University
三天之前被人闯入
was broken into three days ago
他的电脑被砸的稀巴烂
and his computer was smashed.
保安说没有查出是谁干的
Security never found out who did it.
去调查一下
Check into it.
看看能不能发现校园保安遗漏的地方
See if you can find something campus cops missed.
好的
Yeah.
看上去那个办公室或是公文包里有什么
Sounds like something in that office or briefcase
值得下杀手的东西
was worth killing for.
那就查明是什么  探长
Then find out what, detective.
还有  让他妻子同意移交他的遗体
And get the wife to release his body.
是的  长官
Yes, sir.
我不能那么做
I can't do it.
我必须尊重莱斯特的遗愿
I have to honor Lester's wishes.
哈密顿太太  你明不明白
Mrs. Hamilton, you do understand
没有你丈夫的遗体
that without your husband's body,
我们可能无法解决他的谋杀案
we might not be able to solve his murder?
如果冷冻被中断
If preservation is discontinued,
他就永远的走了
he's gonna be gone forever.
恕我直言  他已经离开人世了
With all due respect, he already is gone forever.
莱斯特不是这么认为的
Lester would dispute that.
我们在哈德逊大学做了20多年的同事
He and I have been colleagues at Hudson for 20 years now.
他真的很相信这些
And, uh, he's a true believer.
对他来说  延长寿命
For him, the keys to life extension,
和起死回生的关键  是可以找到的
to reversing death itself, were within reach,
所以他绝对不会放弃重生的机会
so he would never give up his chance at revival.
你知道他为什么选择研究延长寿命吗
Do you know why he chose to focus on life extension?
我们疯狂地爱着对方
We fell madly in love with each other.
他对我说一辈子在一起还不够
He told me that one lifetime together wasn't enough.
他想要更多的时间
He wanted more.
我也是
So do I.
哈密顿太太  我们认为杀死你丈夫的人
Mrs. Hamilton, we think that whoever killed your husband
很可能偷走了他的公文包
might have stolen his briefcase.
你知道里面是什么吗
Do you know what was in it?
是仙果项目的研究资料
His research for the Ambrosia Project.
他总是随身带着
He always had it with him.
仙果是指
Ambrosia as in
希腊神话中众神为获得永生而吃的食物吗
the food Greek gods ate to achieve immortality?
这个项目具体是什么
And what was the Ambrosia Project exactly?
菲利普  你能解释下吗
Philip, how would you explain it?
好吧  虽然这并非我的研究领域
Well, it's a little outside my wheelhouse,
莱斯特正在开发
but Lester was developing
一种药物植入剂  可以让身体
pharmaceutical implants that cause the body
产生鲜活的  而非衰老的细胞
to produce young cells instead of aging ones.
如果成功
He expected it to extend
可将人类的寿命延长十年
the human lifespan by ten years.
这样的疗法能给大医药公司带来滚滚财源
A treatment like that would be worth a fortune to big pharma.
几十亿
Billions.
不过大部分利润本会流进博阿·兰道夫的腰包
Though most of the money would have gone to Beau Randolph.
博阿·兰道夫
Beau Randolph?
那个《疯狂女大学生》的制作人吗
The guy behind "College Girls Gone Crazy"?
怎么会...
How is...
怎么会和一个色情片大亨扯上关系
How is a porn mogul connected to all this?
因为我们不过问研发资金的来源
'Cause researchers take our funding where we can get it.
兰道夫靠色情片大发横财
Randolph made a killing in porn,
现在他又自诩风险投资家
and now he fancies himself a venture capitalist.
莱斯特的研究由他出资支持
He is funding Lester's research, you know?
现在不是了  莱斯特已和他一刀两断
He was. Lester cut all ties with him.
为什么
And why is that?
莱斯特想用开源的研究方式
Lester wanted to take an open-source approach--
在网上公开他的成果
publish his research online,
与才智相当的人共同开发  加速进程
and then develop it with his peers to speed up the process.
那样的话  没人能持有最终成果的专利权
And that way, no one could hold a patent on the results.
兰道夫对此有何反应
And how did Randolph feel about that?
他们为此争吵得很凶
Oh, they had awful fights about it,
但莱斯特立场坚定
but Lester was adamant.
事实上  他原定在今天将数据上传
In fact, he was supposed to upload the data today.
你丈夫和
When did your husband
兰道夫先生什么时闹翻的
and Mr. Randolph have their falling out?
三天前
Three days ago.
三天前  正好是有人闯入他办公室的那天
Three days ago--that's when his office was broken in to.
博阿·兰道夫确实令人不齿  但...
Beau Randolph is distasteful, of course, but...
你们真的认为...
Do you really think...
我认为损失数十亿美元
I think that losing billions of dollars
绝对是杀人动机
is motive for murder.
博阿·兰道夫不仅有一把
So not only is Beau Randolph, the proud owner
史密斯&威尔森45口径自动手枪
of a Smith & Wesson .45 automatic...
这个口径很大
Which is a large enough caliber
足以造成死者身上的射入伤口
to have created that entry wound in our victim.
他还有持枪许可
He also has a carry permit.
什么  我都拿不到持枪许可
Wh--I couldn't even get a carry permit.
-他怎么弄到的  -不容易啊
- How did he get one? - The hard way.
不少人看到自己的女友出现在他的电影里
Several guys saw their girlfriends in his videos
就把他打得满地找牙
and beat the hell out of him.
不嫉妒了
No longer jealous.
但枪不足以把他跟凶案连在一起
The gun still doesn't tie him to our murder.
确实  不过有其他线索
Yeah, but this might.
死者的信用卡有一笔开销
A charge on our vic's credit card.
今早六点半  他在美杜莎餐馆吃的早饭
6:30 this morning, he bought breakfast at Medusa Diner.
我跟服务员谈了谈  你猜谁跟他在一起
I talked to the waitress. Guess who was with him.
博阿·兰道夫
Beau Randolph.
两人吵得不可开交
And there was a whole lot of yelling going on.
六点半  十分钟后哈密顿被枪杀
6:30, that's 10 minutes before Hamilton was shot.
我们走  卡塞尔
Come on, Castle.
仙果项目
The Ambrosia Project--
听着像罗伯特·陆德伦的小说
It sounds like a Robert Ludlum novel
家财万贯的花花公子
where the millionaire playboy
为了拿到永生的秘法
kills a researcher to get his hands
而杀了一名科学家
on the secret formula for eternal life.
十年可不算是永生
Yeah, well, ten years is not eternal life.
你会做吗  会接受植入手术吗
Would you do it? Would you get the implants?
姐的身材还要植什么吗
I don't think I need 'em.
我是说...
I mean the...
药物植入
Pharmaceutical implants.
让我活到一百岁  而不是九十
So I could live to 100 instead of 90?
不了  我还是算了
No, I think I will pass.
如果能让你在接下来的十年里
What if you could stay the same way you are now
保持现在的样貌呢
for the next ten years?
我不想样貌一成不变
I don't want to stay the same.
你怎么会不想多活十年呢
How could you not want ten extra years?
我学到的一个道理就是
Well, one thing I've learned is that
你永远不知道你还能活多久
you never know how much time you have.
如果我知道能活更久
And if I thought I had more,
说不定就会浪费掉
I just might end up wasting it.
你绝对需要药物植入
Yeah, you're gonna need to get those implants,
不然的话  你在慢慢变老
otherwise, you'll get older
而十年后  我还是老样子
and ten years from now, I'll still be exactly the same.
你本来不就长不大吗
Isn't that how you'll be anyway?
贝克特探长
Detective Beckett.
兰道夫先生一会就到
Mr. Randolph will be right out.
很好  谢谢
Great. Thank you.
参加《女生联谊会枕头大战7》的各位到后面来
Everyone here for "Sorority Pillow Fight #7," come on back.
这些女孩
Someone needs to get these girls
真该穿点遮体的衣服了
clothes made of actual fabric.
你从何时起  对这些几乎
When did you become so judgmental
一丝不挂的女人  会冷言讽刺了
about practically naked women?
自从我女儿到了上大学的年纪
Since my daughter hit college age.
他来了
And there he is--
纯洁校园亵渎者
Defiler of coeds.
贝克特探长
Detective Beckett.
我是博阿·兰道夫
Beau Randolph.
你确定你不是来参加
Are you sure you're not here to audition
《"博士后"扮医生》系列试镜的吗
for my "Post-docs Play Doctor" series?
不是
No.
有什么我能做的吗
Then what can I do for you?
有些关于莱斯特·哈密顿的问题要问你
You can answer a few questions about Lester Hamilton.
比如你为何杀了他
Like why did you kill him?
是的  今早在那家餐馆
Yeah, I was with Professor Hamilton
我和哈密顿教授在一起
at the diner this morning.
那里难以下咽的早饭才叫犯罪
The only crime was how bad the food was.
有证人说你们大吵一架
Witnesses say that you fought.
没错
That's right.
我向他的研究投了几百万
I'd sunk millions into his research,
突然之间  他却要免费公开一切
and suddenly, he wants to give it all away?
如果说网络色情片事业教会了我什么
If there's one thing Internet porn has taught me,
那就是免费可赚不到钱
you don't get rich by giving it away.
所以你就杀了他吗
Is that why you killed him,
好赶在他上传资料前
so you could secure Ambrosia
保证仙果研究不会泄露
before he uploaded it for everyone to see?
所以我回家后  给我的律师打电话
That's why I walked home and called my lawyer
签发一张禁令
to issue an injunction.
门卫说你7点10分回到家
The doorman said you came home at 7:10.
没错
Sounds right.
莱斯特·哈密顿在6点40分被杀
Lester Hamilton was killed at 6:40.
你在回家前  有足够的时间
That's plenty of time for you to put two in his chest
给他两枪
before walking home.
我没有杀他  但我知道是谁干的
I didn't kill him, but I know who did.
真的吗
Do you really?
介意透露一下吗
Would you care to share?
上个月  国立卫生研究院驳回了
Look, last month, the N.I.H. rejected
他的人体试验申请
him for human testing.
我跟他说这只是暂时的
Now I told him the setback was temporary.
但他说他即将有所突破
But he said he was too close to a breakthrough.
他不会让一帮官僚体制下的科学家
And he wasn't gonna let a bunch of bureaucratic scientists
阻碍他的事业
get in his way.
一周后
A week later,
我注意到在我给他设的账户里
I notice $100,000 missing
少了十万美元
from the account I set up for him.
你认为他在获得许可前  就进行人体试验
You think he went ahead with human testing without approval.
是的
Yes...
秘密进行
In secret.
然后他就让我滚蛋
And then he tells me to take a hike.
我认为他确实有突破了
I think he had that breakthrough.
我认为仙果项目成功了
I think the Ambrosia Project worked.
很有意思的故事  兰道夫先生
That's a very interesting theory, Mr. Randolph.
但你还没有告诉我们
But you still haven't told us
你认为谁杀了哈密顿
who you think killed Hamilton.
如果他在做非法试验
If he was doing illegal testing,
试验对象从哪里来
where were his test subjects coming from?
我只能跟你说
I can tell you this,
肯定不是身家清白的大学生
they weren't clean-cut college kids.
是那些不介意被人扎针
They're the kind of folks who don't mind needles
又极可能持有枪支的人
and are likely to possess firearms.
与你不同的是  我的观点
Here's my view, and unlike yours,
是基于事实的
mine is based on fact--
你在哈密顿的研究上花了几百万
You sunk millions of dollars into Hamilton's research,
而正当你认为哈密顿...
and just as you thought that Hamilton...
有所突破时  他却踢你出局
was making a breakthrough, he cut you off.
这叫动机
That is motive.
你有一把大口径枪支
You have a large-caliber gun.
而哈密顿正是死在大口径枪下
Hamilton just happened to have been shot with a large-caliber gun.
这叫手段
That is means.
而哈密顿死前十分钟
And you were seen arguing with Hamilton
有人看到你们争执
ten minutes before he was killed.
这叫时机
That is opportunity.
这是你的推测  探长
It's conjecture, detective.
你没有证据
You have no proof.
事实上  我有
Actually, I do.
鉴证组刚刚证实你的点45口径枪
C.S.U. just found that your 45-caliber gun
今早曾开过枪
was fired this morning.
你知道这叫什么吗
You know what we call that?
铁证如"枪"
The smoking gun.
这跟哈密顿毫无关系
Well, that had nothing to do with Hamilton.
今早我屋顶上有一群鸽子
There was a flock of pigeons on my roof this morning,
唧唧喳喳的
squawking,
我还想睡觉呢
and I was trying to sleep.
鸽子
Pigeons?
那就是你的辩词吗
That's what you're gonna go with?
鉴于你们唯一的证据
Given that the only evidence you have
被冻在哈密顿先生的身体里了
is frozen inside Mr. Hamilton,
没错
yeah,
那就是我的辩词
that's what I'm going with.
与此同时
In the meantime,
我要找我的律师来
I'd like my lawyer.
自以为是  自命不凡的混蛋
Smug, self-satisfied son of a bitch.
没错  但是枪击没有目击证人
Yes, but with no witness to the shooting,
我们只有他的枪
all we've got is a gun.
没有子弹又做不了弹道分析
Since we can't match ballistics without the bullets,
我们都不能证明那就是凶器
we can't even prove it's the murder weapon.
谢谢你  卡塞尔先生  我知道弹道是怎么回事
Thank you, Mr. Castle. I know how ballistics works.
长官  我们需要他的尸体
Sir, we need that body,
否则就不能结案
otherwise, we don't have a case.
我会给地方检察官打电话
I'll call the D.A.
我不在乎判例法怎么模糊不清
I don't care if case law's murky.
我们抓到嫌疑人了
We have a suspect now.
这么说吧  伙计们
Here's the deal, boys--
地方检察官办公室认为我们现在
the D.A.'s office believes that we currently
有足够的理由拿到一张搜查令
have sufficient grounds to obtain a warrant
带走并扣押莱斯特·哈密顿的尸体
and take custody of Lester Hamilton's body
作为他谋杀案的证据
as evidence in his murder investigation.
你知道我们会据理力争的吧
You know we'll fight you, right?
你真的甘愿冒风险吗
Do you really want to risk
判例法也许会基于这种极端情况
that case law will be established on the basis
确立新法
of these extraordinary circumstances?
而那时  判例法会限制你们所有委托人的权利
Case law that will limit the rights of all your clients.
我希望我们能找到其他解决办法
Now I'm hoping that we can find another way,
但是我必须拿到那具尸体
but I need that body.
我们不能放弃委托人
We can't surrender our client's chance
未来过上美满生活的机会
at a long, productive future life
就因为这给州政府带来不便
because it proves inconvenient for the state.
那我敢肯定
Then I'm sure
地方检察官办公室会很快联系你的
you'll be hearing from the district attorney's office shortly.
或许还有别的办法
There may be another way.
我们入棺前X光检查发现哈密顿的心脏
Our admittance X-rays show that Hamilton's heart
已被子弹损坏
was damaged by the bullets.
所以保存尸身便不再是重点了
So maintaining the body is no longer a priority.
人体冷冻重在保存大脑
Cryonics is mostly about preserving the brain.
等到科技发展到可以复活哈密顿时
By the time the technology exists to revive Hamilton,
我们肯定能使身体再生了
we'll surely be able to regenerate our bodies.
总之呢
Bottom line--
我们可以不上法庭
we can keep the courts out of this,
而你们也能马上拿到哈密顿的尸身
and you can have Hamilton's body immediately
前提是你们同意把他的头
if you agree to leave his head
留在帕威的仓库里
in storage at Passageway.
成交
Then we have a deal.
现在只要确认兰道夫的枪是凶器就行了
Now all we need to do is match ballistics to Randolph's gun.
不匹配
They're not a match.
什么叫不匹配
What do you mean, they're not a match?
就是说莱斯特·哈密顿胸口里的子弹
I mean, the bullets in Lester Hamilton's chest
不是博阿·兰道夫的枪里射出的
were not fired by Beau Randolph's gun.
你确定吗
Are you sure?
不  我就是整天坐在这儿编瞎话
No, I just sit down here all day and make stuff up.
我当然确定
Of course I'm sure.
抱歉
Sorry.
这是弹道报告
Here's the ballistics report.
兰道夫的枪口径是点45
Randolph's gun is a .45.
杀死无头先生的是把点38
Headless here was shot with a .38.
拿到尸身本该帮我们结案的
Getting that body was supposed to sew our case up
而不是让它乱成一团
not blow it apart.
子弹怎么会不匹配呢
How can those bullets not match?
我有个理论  但我想你不会喜欢的
I have a theory, but you're not gonna like it.
我现在是什么都愿意听
You know, I'm open to anything right now.
兰道夫是清白的
Randolph is innocent.
你说对了  我不喜欢
Yeah, you're right. I don't like it.
兰道夫肯定不是唯一垂涎哈密顿的研究的人
Randolph can't be the only one who wanted Hamilton's research.
或许是一位生命延长研究的竞争者
Maybe a competing life-extension researcher?
是啊  我要给他妻子打电话
Maybe. I'm gonna call his wife up...
问问她有什么了解
and see what she knows.
阿丽克西斯
你在哪  爸爸
是阿丽克西斯吗
Alexis?
对  她有点失控了
Yeah, she's spinning out.
她想要的东西还从未失手过
She's never not gotten something she set her sights on.
你介意我...
Do you mind if I--
不介意  你现在该去陪她
No, no. You should be with her now.
-真的没事吗  -没事  卡塞尔
- You're sure? - Yeah, Castle.
我想没有你  撑几个小时我还是可以的
I think I can manage without you for a few hours.
好吧  别这么高兴
Right. Don't look so happy about it.
莱恩  干嘛呢  伙计  去哪了
Yo, Ryan. What's up, man? Where you been?
去了趟大学
Down at the college,
查查哈密顿办公室的闯入事件
running down that break-in in Hamilton's office.
听我说
So listen to this...
这是啥
What the hell is this?
这  我的朋友  是博阿·兰道夫的不在场证明
That, my friend, is Beau Randolph's alibi.
那只被杀的鸽子
A dead pigeon?
鉴证组在他家楼顶找到的
C.S.U. found it on the roof of his building
腹中还留着他点45口径枪射出的子弹
with a slug in its belly from his .45.
真的假的
Seriously?
这么说兰道夫还真是个凶手
So Randolph really did commit murder, huh?
是啊  刚写完他虐待动物的报告
Yeah. Just writing him up for animal cruelty right now.
或许还来得及冷冻这个小家伙
Maybe there's still time to cryonically freeze the little guy.
哈密顿办公室怎么了
Hamilton's office?
对了
Yeah.
首先  哈德逊大学那些个校警
So first off, Hudson's campus cops--
真不是盖的  我知道我们将来要是
wow-- I know what we'll be doing
挨整离队  惩奸除恶都成了浮云该去干嘛了
when we're fried and don't care anymore.
至少他们还知道封装证据呢
At least they bagged the evidence.
我们在哈密顿被砸坏的电脑上找到了指纹
We were able to pull prints off Hamilton's smashed computer
与他的一名学生艾迪·派克的指纹相匹配
they match one of his studtsts-- an Eddie Peck.
全优生  无犯罪记录
Straight A's, no record.
那他干嘛要闯进哈密顿的办公室
Then what was he doing breaking into Hamilton's office
砸烂他的电脑
and smash his computer?
你听我说  看看能不能解答你的疑问
Tell me if this answer your question.
他父亲  是位首席研究员
His father is a lead researcher
在史密斯·布莱尔制药公司工作
at Smith Briar Pharmaceuticals.
那是大型制药公司
Big pharma.
小派克为老派克去偷哈密顿的研究
Young Peck stoled Hamilton's research for his dad.
眼熟吗  派克
They look familiar Peck?
不该陌生啊  上面都是你的指纹
It should. Got your prints all over it.
我们知道你闯入哈密顿的办公室
We know you broke into Hamilton's office.
你去找什么了
What were you looking for?
我发誓  本不该是这样的
It wasn't supposed to try out this way, I swear.
我只是  不想让他失望
I just--I didn't want to be a disappointment.
谁  你父亲吗
To who, your father?
你这么做是为了他  对吗
You did this for him, didn't you?
你不知道他什么样
You don't know what he's like.
-你怎么处理他的研究了  -什么研究
- What did you do with the research? - What research?
哈密顿教授的研究  仙果项目
Professor Hamilton's, the Ambrosia Project.
就在他的公文包里
It was inside his briefcase,
所以你才杀了他  对吗
and that's why you killed him, isn't it?
杀他  不不
Killed him? No, no.
我求他改我的成绩
I asked him to change my grade.
你说什么
Excuse me?
我这学期初  遇到一个女孩  苏西
I met this girl--Suzy--at the beginning of the semester.
我之前从没恋爱过  我完全陷进去了
I'd never been in love before, but I fell hard, man.
我们不在一起时
When I wasn't with her,
我能做的只是幻想和她在一起
all I could do was daydream about her, you know?
你到底在说什么
What the hell are you talking about?
你的恋情和这个案件有什么关系
What does your love life have to do with any of this?
因为苏西的原因  我没有准备
'Cause of Suzy, I didn't study for
哈密顿教授的期中考试
Professor Hamilton's midterm.
然后我考了个F  我们家从没有人考过F
I got an "F." We don't get F's in my family,
特别是生物课  我爸爸会宰了我的
especially in bio? My father would kill me.
所以我偷溜进哈密顿的办公室
So I broke in to Hamilton's office
想把他电脑里登记的成绩改掉
and tried to change the grade in his computer,
但是我不知道他的密码
but I didn't know his password.
然后我气急败坏地把电脑扔到墙上去了
I got frustrated and threw it against the wall.
别对我说谎  派克
Don't you lie to me, Peck.
哈密顿的成绩单上写着你在期中考试得了A
Hamilton's grade report said you got an "A" on his midterm.
那是因为第二天下课
That's 'cause after class the next day,
我跟踪他  想要鼓起勇气
I followed him, tried to work up the courage
求他帮我改成绩
to beg him to change my grade.
但是我还没有鼓足勇气
But before I could,
我们就到了一个很恐怖的地方
we were in this scary neighborhood,
他进了一个破烂旅馆
and he went into this seedy hotel.
他在那干什么
And what was he doing there?
我不知道
I don't know.
但当他一小时之后走出来的时候
But he came out, like, an hour later,
他看到了我  像疯了一样
and when he saw me, he totally wigged.
就好像眼睛都要瞪出来了一样
Like eyes-popping-out-of-his-head crazy.
他主动提出帮我改成绩
He--he offered to change my "F" to an "A"
条件是  我不能告诉任何人他在那里
in exchange for me never telling anyone he was there.
旅馆的名字是什么
This hotel have a name?
130街旅馆
The 130th street inn.
住在24号房那个珠子眼的小个子
That little beady-eyed guy in 24,
是个很厉害的科学家吗
a big-time scientist?
别逗了
Get out.
他来这里多久了
How long had he been coming here?
上个月开始  他定了一整个月
Ah, booked his room solid for the last month.
现金支付
Paid cash.
一整个月他都在这里做什么
What was he doing here for a month?
亲爱的  这是个"不问  不说"的旅馆
Sweet pea, this is a "Don't ask, don't tell" hotel.
就是说你没问  那你能告诉我们什么
So you didn't ask, but could you tell?
这位老兄三令五申
Little dude made a big deal
无论什么情况  都不能进他的房间
about no one ever going into his room for any reason,
连打扫房间都不行
not even to clean.
我猜他有收集充气娃娃或者什么的
Ah, I figured he had a blow-up doll collection or something.
《无菌罩内的少年》[美国电影]的感觉唉
This some boy-in-the-plastic-bubble thing or what?
告诉你们  这里我不会打扫的
I'll tell you something, I am not cleaning this up.
请退后  夫人
Please stay back, ma'am.
让我退后  我是相当乐意啊
Twist my arm.
老兄  最好别出现残肢
Dude, there better not be body parts in there.
进去吧
Just...
解剖刀
Scalpels...
手术钻
Drill.
那是激光器吗
Is that a laser?
利多卡因  这是种麻醉剂
Lidocaine. That's an anesthetic.
注射器
Syringes?
这是个手术室  兄弟
It's an operating room, bro.
哈密顿在给谁做手术  为什么选这里
Who the hell was Hamilton operating on, and why here?
他的仙果项目
His Ambrosia Project.
他说他的研究即将有重大的突破
He said he was on the verge of a major breakthrough
但是进行人体试验的申请被拒绝了
but got turned down for human testing.
看起来博阿·兰道夫是对的
Looks like Beau Randolph was right.
哈密顿不想再等下去了
Hamilton decided not to wait.
谁会报名参加一个未经试验的外科手术
Who would sign up for an illegal experimentation
做非法的试验研究呢
of an untested surgical procedure?
不知道  但如果它能让你更开心  活得更久
Oh, I don't know. If it'd make you feel better, live longer,
管他呢  我会试试的
Hell, I'd give it a try.
不过不是在破旅馆里面  要在五星级宾馆里
Though not in a sleazy hotel. I need five stars.
今早见到阿丽克西斯了吗
Any sign of Alexis this morning?
没见着
Oh. No.
昨晚我到家的时候  她在沙发上睡着了
When I got home last night, she was sacked out on the couch.
我把她抱上床的  这是这么些年来的第一次
I had to carry her up to bed. That's the first time in years.
可怜的孩子
Poor baby.
她收到拒信之后就消极得很
She hasn't been herself since getting that rejection.
甜心  盒子里装的什么啊
Hey, sweetheart. What's in the box?
我这一生的谎言
My life of lies.
我要把它们全部丢掉
I'm throwing it all out.
亲爱的  你所有的奖吗  你为这些付出了很多
Oh, honey, all your awards? You worked hard for these.
是吗
Did I?
这里一半都是参与奖奖杯
Half of them are participation trophies.
超级皮威足球赛
Super-Pee-Wee soccer.
你记得那次
You remember the time...
你顶进一个球  自己都没发现吗
you scored a goal off your head, and you didn't even realize it?
我还因此拿了一座奖杯吗
And I got a trophy for that?
我们一场比赛都没赢过
We didn't even win a single game.
拜托  这些事你不必记得的
Oh, come on. You weren't supposed to keep score.
但是斯坦福有记录啊
Yeah? Well, Stanford keeps score.
拜托  有些是实实在在的成就
Come on, let's see some of these awards are for actual achievements--
富兰克林中学拼字比赛冠军
Franklin Middle School spelling bee champ,
马洛私立高中法语奖
Marlowe Prep French Award.
我要的是斯坦福
The one I wanted was Stanford.
亲爱的  我知道阿什利要去斯坦福
Sweetheart, I-I know Ashley is going to Stanford--
这跟阿什利没关系
This has nothing to do with ashley!
是我  爸爸  我是个失败者
It's me, dad! I'm a failure!
你没被一所大学录取
Hey, just because you didn't get into one school
并不能说明你就是个失败者啊
does not make you a failure.
但你要接受这个现实  然后继续生活
But you are gonna have to accept that you didn't get in and move on.
怎么继续
How?
我只想给她我从未有过的童年
I just wanted to give her the childhood I never had.
也许我保护过度了
Maybe I overprotected her.
你给了她一个完美的童年  卡塞尔
You gave her a great childhood, Castle.
这不是件坏事
It's not a bad thing.
无法接受被拒绝可不是好事
Not if she's incapable of handling rejection.
我们都会有伤心的时候
Look, we all get our hearts broken eventually.
给她点时间  她会想明白的
Just give her some time. She'll find her way.
只要她别去博阿·兰道夫那里试镜就行
As long as she doesn't end up auditioning for Beau Randolph.
哈密顿的那间骇人旅店
So any word on what was going on
调查的如何了
in Hamilton's hotel of horrors?
蕾妮正在给沾血的手术器材做化验
Lanie's running test results on the bloody instruments,
但是目前为止  似乎有一个实验对象
But so far, it looks like at least one test subject
对结果不是很满意
wasn't pleased with the results.
鉴证组在旅店里发现了这个
C.S.U. found that note in the hotel.
"你跟我说这会成功  我相信了你"
"You told me this would work. I trusted you."
看来博阿·兰道夫是对的
Looks like Beau Randolph was right.
哈密顿在做人体实验
Hamilton was doing human testing.
看来它进行得没有计划的那么顺利
Looks like it didn't go as planned.
也许科学怪人的怪物
Maybe Frankenstein's monster
回来把科学怪人杀了
came back and killed Frankenstein.
无法确认写纸条的是谁
No luck I.D.'ing the note's author.
鉴定组在房间里找到的唯一指纹是哈密顿的
The only prints C.S.U. found in the room were Hamilton's.
哈密顿老婆那边呢
What about Hamilton's wife?
我们询问过她  他的同事
We checked with her, his colleagues,
和他的学生
and his students.
没人知道他在做秘密试验
No one even knew he was doing any secret research.
一定有人知道  在旅店附近进行排查
Well, someone knew about it. Canvass around the hotel.
那个地区无家可归的人很多
There's a big homeless population in the area.
也许他就是在那里找到的试验对象
Maybe that's where he got his subjects.
在人物层面上  我没搞懂哈密顿
You know, I don't get Hamilton on a character level.
为什么他要拿他的声望和人身安全来冒险
Why would he risk his reputation, his safety,
在廉价旅馆里做非法试验呢
to do illegal testing in some flophouse?
他已经准备好公布他的研究
I mean, he was ready to give away his research,
所以他不是为了钱
so it wasn't the money.
他为什么这么着急呢
Why was he in such a big rush?
蕾妮那边DNA化验结果出来了
Lanie's got the D.N.A. results.
查出哈密顿的试验对象是谁了吗
So the labs tell us who Hamilton's test subjects were?
从针头和手术钻上提取的DNA的
Preliminary D.N.A. results
初步化验结果显示
from the needles and the drill show the D.N.A.
血迹属于同一个人
is all from the same person--
莱斯特·哈密顿
Lester Hamilton.
莱斯特并不是在别人身上做试验
So Lester wasn't doing the procedures on someone else.
是别人在他身上做试验
Someone was doing them to him.
然后他决定不能光说不练
And he decided to put his money where his mouth was,
用他自己做实验品
using himself as a test subject.
那么给他做试验的人又是谁呢
But then who was doing the procedures on him?
这又怎么导致他被杀呢
And how did it even get him killed?
我能不能
Can I just--
也许这个治疗方案成功了
Maybe the treatment was a success.
哈密顿意识到他就要
Hamilton realized he was on the cusp
取得延长寿命技术领域的革命性突破
of a revolutionary life-extension breakthrough--
老天
Oh, my gosh--
你能相...
Could you be--
伙计们
Guys!
停一下
Hold up.
别你一句我一句的了
Stop doing that thing you do for one second.
谢谢
Thank you.
你推理我分析尽管很可爱
Now all of the theorizing is cute as usual.
但是我们还有一个疑点
But we've got a problem.
怎么说
How so?
仙果项目的植入物
The Ambrosia Project implant
理应是植入到患者手臂上的
is supposed to be in the patient's arm.
而我检查过他的手臂
I checked his arms, in fact,
实际上  我检查过哈密顿身体的每一寸
I checked every inch of Hamilton's body.
根本没找到有任何植入点或是伤口
There were no intrusions or wounds anywhere.
我不明白
I don't understand.
你不是说针头上检测出了他的DNA吗
I thought you said the needles had his D.N.A.
是啊
They do.
还有他的脑浆
And his brain matter, too.
这么说不管他们做了什么  是在他脑袋上进行的
So whatever they were doing, they were doing to his head?
这也是哈密顿身上
Which is the only part of Hamilton's body
你唯一没有检查过的地方
that you haven't checked yet.
把他的头给我拿来
Get me his head,
我就可以把整件事的来龙去脉搞清楚
and I can tell you what this is all about.
我们已经达成协议了
We had an agreement.
那个时候  哈密顿先生的头
That was before, when Mr. Hamilton's head
跟这个案子毫不相关
wasn't relevant to this case.
-现在情况不同了  -拜托你了
- Now it is.  - Please.
维斯博士  我有法庭的许可令
Dr. Weiss, I have a warrant,
你可以拿去查看一番
and you're welcome to read it.
我知道这是合法的
I know it's legal,
但请考虑一下莱斯特·哈密顿的遗愿
but think of Lester Hamilton's wishes.
现在最重要的是找到凶手
His wishes right now
而不是遵从他的遗愿
come second to this murder investigation.
把门打开
Now open the door.
我会尽量谨慎  不对他的头造成任何损害  维斯博士
I'll be as minimally invasive as possible, Dr. Weiss.
任何的损害都会毁掉他的记忆
Any invasion at all will destroy memory,
性格和脑部的关键性能
personality, vital functions.
天啊
Oh, my god.
怎么了
What is it?
头不见了
It's gone.
低温储藏器应该就放在这的
The thermal storage unit should be right there.
你开什么玩笑
You gotta be kidding me.
你是说你把他的头弄丢了吗
Are you saying, you lost his head?
我不明白
I don't understand.
我丈夫的头怎么会不见了呢
How does my husband's head just go missing?
我们正在调查这件事  哈密顿太太
That's what we're trying to figure out, Mrs. Hamilton.
您知不知道  谁会有可能在130街旅馆里
Do you have any idea who could have operated on him
给他动手术呢
at the 130th Street Inn?
我已经跟贝克特探长说过了
I already told Detective Beckett,
我对此一无所知
I don't know anything about that.
我现在要你马上找到他
Now I need to find him immediately.
我需要确保他的遗愿得以实现
I need to make sure that his wishes are being respected.
我明白  我向你保证
I understand, and I promise you
我们正在竭尽所能...
that we are doing everything that we possibly can --
维斯博士呢  他是那里的负责人
What about Dr. Weiss? He's in charge over there.
你们找他谈过了吗
Have you spoken to him?
贝克特探长正在跟他谈话
Detective Beckett is with him right now.
我跟你一样  对哈密顿的头的
I'm just as concerned about Hamilton's head
下落很关心  探长
as you are, detective.
肯定是有人闯入了我们的储藏室
There must have been a break-in at our storage facility.
有人闯入  真的吗  这就是你的辩词吗
A break-in? Really? Is that what you're going with?
我们那里以前
We've never had anything like this
从来都没发生过这种事
happen to one of our clients.
只有这个说得通
It's the only thing that makes any sense.
我来告诉你什么说得通吧  维斯博士
No, I will tell you what makes sense, Dr. Weiss.
你要不就是在给凶手打掩护
Either you're part of a cover-up,
要不你就是凶手
or you're a murderer,
又或者你两者都是
or both.
什么  我  我为什么要杀人
What? W-why would I kill anyone?
我上有老下有小的
I have a family.
那当你未经允许就从罪案现场
Well, then did you take them into consideration
把尸体转移走的时候
when you colluded in moving a body
你有考虑过你的家人吗
from a murder scene.
那是百年一遇的特殊状况
That was a one-in-a-million circumstance,
再说大家最后不都得到自己想要的东西了嘛
and everyone ended up getting what they needed.
那你告诉我  为什么我在调查的每一步
Then why is it, at every step of this investigation,
都遇到了你的阻挠呢
you have gotten in my way?
哈密顿一死  尸体就被你运走了
Hamilton ends up dead and in your custody.
地检官刚要把尸体转交给我
The D.A.'s about to turn over the body to me,
你便利用谈判  留下了他的头
and you negotiate to keep the head.
我拿着法庭许可令去取回他的头
I get a warrant for the head,
突然间  头又不见了
and suddenly, it ends up missing.
我只是在努力遵循莱斯特·哈密顿的遗愿
The only thing I'm guilty of is trying to protect
把他的尸体进行低温储藏
Lester Hamilton's desire to be cryopreserved.
我对他的谋杀一无所知
I don't know anything about his murder.
你可以跟我的公司去核实
Please check with my company.
肯定是有人闯入了储藏室
There must have been a break-in.
怎么了
What's up?
经查实  昨天半夜
Turns out there was a break-in
有人闯入了帕威的储藏室
at the Passageway storage facility in the middle of the night.
不是吧  他们把头拿走了吗
No way. And they took the head?
这是监控录像  你自己看看吧
Security video. Just watch.
今天凌晨3点32分
Last night, 3:32 a.m.
这是哈密顿的低温储存器吗
Hamilton's storage container?
没错
Yep.
那是谁呀
Who the hell's that?
哈密顿的老朋友兼同事
Hamilton's dear friend and colleague.
博伊德博士
Dr. Boyd.
纽约警署  把门打开  博伊德
NYPD. Open up, Boyd.
我想他不打算开门了
I don't think he's opening up.
他从窗户跳到防火梯上跑了
He went out the window to the fire escape.
还用得着你说吗
Yeah, you think?
人家太兴奋了嘛
Just excited.
头在他手上  贝克特  头在他手上
He's got the head. Beckett, he's got the head.
我看见了
I can see that!
博伊德博士  站住
Dr. Boyd, stop!
不
No!
大头朝下  扎入垃圾箱唉
Talk about taking a header.
我去拿头
I'll get the head.
起来
Get up.
我拿到了  我拿到哈密顿的头了
I got it! I got Hamilton's head.
应该没损坏
I think it's okay.
你因谋杀莱斯特·哈密顿
You are under arrest
而被捕了
for the murder of Lester Hamilton.
我没杀他
I didn't kill him.
我只是想救他而已
I was trying to save his life.
他不会有事的
He's gonna be fine.
那就放心了
That's a relief.
为什么会有人想要偷颗头呢
Why would anyone steal a head?
博伊德博士  你可是被我们逮了个正着呀
So, Dr. Boyd, it seems we caught you red-handed.
我没杀他
I didn't kill him.
那你为什么要偷他的头呢
Well, then why did you steal his head?
难不成你想他了吗
Did you miss him?
我们查到了你在130街的手术室
We know about your operating room at 130th street,
也知道你在哈密顿的头部动了手术
and you were doing surgery on Hamilton's head,
但那手术跟延长寿命完全没有任何关系
but it had nothing to do with life extension.
你要么老实招供
So either you tell me about it,
要么我们就把他的头带回去  自行研究
or we take the head back and we find out on our own.
他一个月前来找我
He came to me a month ago,
说他有很严重的头痛
complaining about severe headaches.
核磁共振显示
An M.R.I. showed
他患有四期恶性胶质瘤
that he had stage IV glioblastoma.
他长了脑瘤吗
A brain tumor?
这种肿瘤无法动手术  也无法治愈
Inoperable, untreatable --
他只剩下几个月的命了
he only had a few months to live.
那他为什么要去找你呢
Well, then why did he go to you?
他为什么不去医院呢
Why didn't he go to a hospital?
因为作为一个科学家
Because as a scientist,
他知道现有医学技术的局限性
he knew the limits of current therapies,
而他对我的研究  纳米遗传疗法
and he was familiar with my work --
颇有了解
nanoparticle genetic therapy.
讲英语
English.
这是专门针对肿瘤的一种疗法
Targeted treatment of tumors.
我的研究距离人体试验还差得远  但是
I'm years away from human testing, but...
他是我最好的朋友
he was my best friend.
我怎么能拒绝他呢
How could I say no to him?
于是你们就在那间小旅店搞了个手术室秘密行事
So you set up shop at the hotel to keep it secret.
这件事要是被人发现了
If anyone found out,
我在大学的终身职位
I'd lose my tenure,
我的研究基金和我的名誉就全都毁了
my funding, reputation.
我们连现成的手术室都不敢用
We couldn't even risk using existing operating suites.
莱斯特发誓  他对他妻子辛西娅都会保密
Lester swore he wouldn't even tell Cynthia.
然后他挪用了博阿·兰道夫的基金
And then he got the money from Beau Randolph's fund
来给你买手术器具
in order to get you your supplies.
没错
Yeah.
我在一个月内
I did...
给他做了五次手术
five procedures over the month.
他的情况有所好转吗
And was he getting better?
没有
No.
在他被害前几天
A few days before he was killed,
我又给他做了个核磁共振  发现他的肿瘤
I did an M.R.I. that showed that the tumor was...
还在扩散
still growing.
治疗失败了
The treatment had failed.
脑瘤  这就是哈密顿想把项目
A brain tumor? That's why Hamilton wanted
放到网上的原因
to put his project online--
希望有人能帮他完成研究
In hopes that someone would finish his research.
是的  我已经让埃斯波西托去查证博伊德的
Yeah, I've got Esposito running down
不在场证明了  以防万一
Boyd's alibi just in case.
阿丽克西斯
Alexis?
怎么了
What's wrong?
一切都乱了
Everything.
你怎么做到的  爸爸
How do you do it, dad?
做什么
Do what?
那封被你裱起来
Well, that letter that you have
挂在办公室的信
framed in your office.
-我第一份手稿的退件信吗  -是的
- My first manuscript rejection. - Yeah.
你怎么能忍受天天对着它
How can you stand having it there?
因为它驱使我前进
Because it drives me.
在黑卒同意出版《枪林弹雨中》之前
And I got 20 more of those before Black Pawn
我还收过另外二十封呢
ever agreed to publish "In A Hail of Bullets."
那封信...
That letter...
那封信让我记得我曾经克服过什么
That letter reminds me of what I've overcome.
被拒绝不代表失败
Rejection isn't failure.
那感觉就像是失败
It sure feels like failure.
不  放弃才是失败
No, failure is giving up.
每个人都有被拒绝的时候
Everybody gets rejected.
你处理拒绝的方式将会决定你何去何从
It's how you handle it that determines where you'll end up.
一直以来  我的目标就是
My whole life has been about making sure
能被任何我想进入的大学录取
I could get into any college I wanted.
现在的目标又是什么呢
What's it about now?
慢慢来
Give it time.
你会找到答案的
You'll figure it out.
她没事吧
She okay?
我们都曾经历过那个年纪吗
Were any of us at that age?
唉  一直烂到不再烂啊
Nah, it'll suck until it doesn't.
是啊  说到"烂"
Yeah, well, speaking of sucking,
博伊德的不在场证明被证实了
Boyd alibied out.
哈密顿被杀的那个早上
He was at a department breakfast
他出席了一个部门早餐会
the morning that Hamilton was killed.
我们都抓到拿着死者的脑袋的那个人了
I mean, we caught the guy with our victim's head.
99%的机率
99 times out of 100,
当你抓到一个人拿着另一个人的脑袋时
you catch someone with a guy's head,
就是他杀害了那个人
he killed the guy.
是啊  博伊德还提供了
Yeah. Well, Boyd also provided
哈密顿脑部的磁共振成像
the MRIs of Hamilton's head.
蕾妮确认那肿瘤
Lanie confirmed that the tumor
将会在几个月之内毁掉他的大脑
would've ravaged his brain in a couple of months.
那么他这是歪打正着地走了大运
So in an odd way, he got lucky.
怎么说
How so?
维斯博士说过人体冷冻
Well, Dr. Weiss said that cryonics
的关键就在于保存大脑
was all about preserving the brain.
如果哈密顿还活着
If Hamilton had lived,
他的大脑就被毁掉了
his brain would've been destroyed.
人体冷冻对他也就没有了用处
Cryonic preservation wouldn't have been an option.
这么说凶手在不经意间
So then our killer inadvertently
挽救了他的未来
saved him for the future.
除非
Unless...
"一辈子在一起还不够"
"One lifetime together wasn't enough."
那就是动机
That's our motive.
或许根本就不是"不经意"
Maybe it wasn't so inadvertent.
谢谢你能过来  哈密顿太太
Thank you for coming in, Mrs. Hamilton.
我知道你已经与博伊德博士谈过了
I understand that you've already spoken with Dr. Boyd.
是的
Yes.
让我大吃一惊
It's a lot to process.
是啊
Yeah.
有什么我能帮忙的
How can I help you?
我们希望你能帮我们
Well, we were hoping that you could
梳理一些刚刚找到的证据
shed some light on some evidence that just came in.
是什么呢
What's that?
你丈夫的电脑  被他学生砸坏的那部
Your husband's computer, the one his student smashed?
警局技术人员
The tech people here
恢复了一份近期的下载项列表
managed to recover a list of recent downloads.
其中包括了
Included on that list
与帕威终止合约的文件
was Passageway's contract termination form.
知道你丈夫为什么会下载那份文件吗
Any idea why your husband would download that?
不知道
No.
那一定是个错误
Well, it must be a mistake.
事实上技术人员已经
Actually, the tech assured us
跟我们确定那列表没问题
that the download list was clean.
你确定他没跟你提过那方面的事吗
Are you sure he didn't say anything to you about that?
我能想出的最佳解释就只有
Because the best I can come up with
你的丈夫决定
is that your husband decided that
在他的大脑彻底损坏之前
working on his research until his brain gave out
继续他的研究要比
was more important to him
冻住自己更为重要
than cryonically preserving himself.
但你不同意他的决定对吗  哈密顿太太
But you disagreed with him, didn't you, Mrs. Hamilton?
我连他有肿瘤都不知道
How could I disagree with him
怎么去反对他的决定呢
when I didn't even know about the tumor?
我认为你是知道的
I think you did know,
那就是你杀死他的原因
and that's why you killed him.
这样他就能在大脑被损坏前
So he would be preserved for the future
被冷冻起来
before his brain was ravaged.
射死他后  你拿走了他的公文箱
After shooting him, you took his briefcase.
太离谱了
This is insane.
这只是你们的疯狂猜测罢了
It's just wild conjecture.
事实上  不只是猜测
Actually, it's not.
毋庸置疑  你把枪处理掉了
You got rid of the gun, of course.
但我们在你住所的地下室
But we found your husband's briefcase
找到了那个公文箱
hidden in your building's basement.
上面有你丈夫的血迹
There were traces of your husband's blood on it.
那个公文箱是我送给他的
I gave him that briefcase...
在我们订婚的时候
when we got engaged.
我不能把它留在那儿
I couldn't just leave it behind.
我察觉事情不对劲
I had known for weeks
已经有几周了
that there was something wrong,
但莱斯特说只是压力大而已
but Lester said it was just stress.
之后在几天前的晚上
And then a couple of nights ago,
他在准备上床前昏倒了
he passed out when he was getting ready for bed.
那会儿他才跟我说了实话
Then he told me the truth.
但...
But...
他已经糊涂了
He wasn't in his right mind.
他过于在意他的研究
He was too concerned about his research.
我必须要保护
I needed to protect
我们的未来
our future...
我们的天长地久
Our eternity together.
那是我们一直以来共同的梦想
It's what we always dreamed of.
探长  你会把这案子当做是
So, detective, would you consider this
激情犯罪吗
to be a crime of passion?
我认为这是为爱而犯罪
I would consider this a crime of love.
很好
Nice.
但那得取决于辛西娅·哈密顿是
Though that would depend on whether Cynthia Hamilton was
爱得痴狂还是疯了
in love or insane.
有时候这二者间只有一线之差
Well, sometimes there's a fine line between the two.
维斯博士
Oh, Dr. Weiss.
你的移交表格准备好了
I have your release forms ready to go.
非常感谢  探长  卡塞尔
I'm grateful, detective. Castle.
你只需要在底部签个名
So I'll just need you to sign down there at the bottom,
针对你以及
and the charges against you
帕威雇员的指控
and your employees at Passageway
就会正式被警局撤销
will officially be dropped by the department.
我很高兴这事解决了
I'm happy to put this behind us.
抱歉
Excuse me.
是生物手表的信号
It's a bio-watch signal.
一位客户刚刚倒下了
A client has just flatlined.
-这真是奇怪了  -怎么了
- Well, that's strange. - What is it?
信号
The signal--
是从这座楼里传来的
It's coming from inside this building.
她右手的戒指
The ring on her right hand.
氰化物药片
Cyanide pill.
贝克特探长
Detective Beckett,
请求你允许我的技术人员
Permission to have my technicians
来把她接走
come and get her?
当然  没问题
Yes, of course.
他们如在一百年  甚至是一千年后重聚
Wouldn't it be something if they reunited
将是很美妙的事  不是吗
a hundred, even a thousand years from now?
一切皆有可能
Well, anything's possible.
你真的相信吗
You really believe that?
伟大的爱情故事不都是如此吗
That's what the great love stories are about, right,
克服一切艰难险阻
beating the odds?
我希望他们能再见
I hope they make it.
我也是
Me, too.